# Saoirse Mullan

# Product Designer (UX,UI)

Belfast, Northern Ireland saoirsemullan.com saoirse.mullan79@gmail.com 07565895806

### Introduction

I am a driven and enthusiastic UX designer. I design intuituve digital products with a focus on creating a meaningful user experience. I work through every stage of the UX and UI design process, from conducting research to understand user needs, creating wireframes and prototypes, and testing designs with users.

### **Experience**

## UX/UI Designer, Aflac Belfast

May 2021 - Present

At Aflac, I help create and deliver exceptional customer experiences through redesigning our front end app. I'm able to effectively translate business problems into intuitive experiences and interaction flows, while supporting the UX Coach, Product Owner and wider team on UX/UI strategy, idea generation and design. Working across the entire UX/UI process from ideation and user research to wireframing and prototyping. I value working closely with the developers on the team and place importance on conducting research through usability testing at all stages of the design process and compiling this into our research repository, Dovetail.

### UX/UI Designer, loyalBe

June 2020 - March 2021

Led the UX/UI design for a fintech app as the sole designer on a team of 3 developers and one PM. Designed the various user interfaces (websites, native apps and customer dashboard). Transformed the consumer-facing website (loyalbe.io) to more accurately support user needs and meet business goals. Designed digital and print marketing assets. My job was to improve the quality of interaction between loyalBe users and customers and all aspects of loyalBe, including at each touchpoint.

**Digital Designer,** Ulster University Belfast September 2019 – April 2020

Web Design Intern, Ulster University Jordanstown September 2018 – July 2019

### **Education**

### BDes (Hons) Interaction Design Ulster University, Belfast School of Art

September 2019 - May 2020

First Class Honours and Diploma in Professional Practice with Commendation.

**Modules:** Interaction Design, Designing with Content, UX & UI, Narrative & Storytelling, Dissertation Writing and Major Project Prototyping.

# BSc Hons Interactive Multimedia Design Ulster University, Jordanstown

September 2016 - June 2019

Completed two years of this degree followed by a placement year for Year 3 before transferring for my final year.

### **Achievements**

### **UX Design Institute**

Professional Diploma in UX Design July 2022

#### Interaction Design Foudation (IDF)

Mobile User Experience Design April 2022

### **IDI** Graduate Design Awards

Shortlist for Interaction Design December 2020

### **Ulster EDGE Excel Award**

May 2020

### **Skills**

- UX Design
- UI Design
- User Research
- Design Thinking
- Prototyping
- Illustration
- Figma
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Basic HTML & CSS
- Sketch
- Dovetail

References available upon request.